Frontend Engineer Elena Ortega

Senior Frontend Engineer with over 8 years of experience with a passion for creating engaging user experiences. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various frontend frameworks. Strong problem-solving skills and a keen eye github.com/elenaorfe linkedin.com/in/elenaorfe elenaorfe@gmail.com EU citizen

WORK EXPERIENCE -



Mobile Application for a Client in the Mobility sector

Developed an iOS and Android application using React Native that successfully amassed over 1.5 million users and achieved top ranking as the 1st free iOS app and secured 4th position on Android in Sweden.

 $React \ Native \cdot React JS \cdot Typescript \cdot Storybook \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot English \cdot GraphQL \cdot Fastlane \cdot GraphQL \cdot Grap$

Web & Mobile Application for a Client in the Prevention of Hazards sector

Led the development of a hazard prevention web platform, integrated interactive floor plans, safety guidelines. Provided primary support during the culmination phase, maintaining React Native iOS and

ReactJS · Typescript · HTML · Scss · React Native · Firebase · NodeJS · Github · Scrum · Trello · English

Web Application for a Client in the University sector

Developed a hate speech detection dashboard to collect and analyze data from multiple social media platforms, incorporating intuitive graphical representations to illustrate hate speech trends and patterns. Angular · Typescript · HTML · Scss · Bootstrap · D3 · Gitlab · Scrum · Jira · English

Web aplication for a Client in the IoT sector

Led the migration from AngularJS to Angular and developed new features for a cloud-based measurement data monitoring system.

Angular JS · Angular · Typescript · HTML · Scss · Bootstrap · Responsive Design · Leaflet maps · i18n · Karma · RESTful API · Webpack Gitlab · Scrum · Jira · English

Web application for a Client in the University

Led a project where I integrated customer-developed API endpoints into a visual map, facilitating the mapping of stores within shopping malls through a custom CMS.

 $Figma \cdot React JS \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Material \, UI \cdot Here \, Maps \cdot i \\ 18n \cdot REST \\ ful \, API \cdot Babel \cdot Webpack \cdot Jest \cdot Selenium \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot Trellogram \\ 18n \cdot REST \\ 1$ English

Web application for internal use

Developed a user interface optimized for office needs, delivering tailored information, and integrated the application with various social media APIs.

 $\mathsf{Sketch} \cdot \mathsf{Marvel} \cdot \mathsf{ReactJS} \cdot \mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{Sass} \cdot \mathsf{Material} \, \mathsf{UI} \cdot \mathsf{Bitbucket} \cdot \mathsf{Scrum} \cdot \mathsf{Trello} \cdot \mathsf{English}$



June 2015 - December 2018

Web application for a Client in the Insurance sector

Led the digital transformation initiative for one of the largest insurance groups in Austria, Central, and Eastern Europe, spearheading the definition, analysis, and implementation of software products.

 $Angular JS \cdot EC6 \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Bootstrap \cdot Responsive \ Design \cdot Handlebars \cdot RESTful \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot API \cdot Git$

Web application for a Client in the Bank sector

Engaged in the digital transformation of a significant financial group, involving analysis of customer requirements, enhancement of form-based workflows, task estimation, form modeling, and frontend

Web application for a Client in the Bank sector.

05.2016 - 04.2017

Developed a credit card portal, involving analysis of customer requirements and tasks estimation, followed by frontend development.

 $English \cdot AngularJS \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Bootstrap \cdot Responsive \ Design \cdot RESTful \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot English \cdot Management \ API \cdot Github \cdot Management \$

R&D Projects

06.2015 - 04.2016

Implemented new features and enhancements for company products within the R&D department, utilizing MV* architecture, integrating social networks into a multichannel platform, and incorporating a workflow engine into a Java application.

AngularJS · HTML · CSS · Mocha · Facebook API · Twitter API · Yammer API · Java · Oracle D · Activiti · Alfresco · English

SIDE PROJECTS -

Portfolio Website

Created a portfolio website using Next.js with Tailwind CSS, integrated an OpenAI-powered chatbot for natural conversations, and deployed the project on

 $Next.js \cdot Typescript \cdot Tailwind \cdot Sass \cdot Vercel \cdot a11y \cdot OpenAl \ API \cdot D3$

Architecture and interior design

https://www.doscestudio.com

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next.js with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

Next.js · Typescript · Tailwind · GraphQL · Wordpress · Web hosting

Portfolio Art Curator

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next.is with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

Next.js · Typescript · Tailwind · GraphQL · Wordpress · Web hosting ·

Scout Association

Developed a WordPress plugin for a website.

 $\mathsf{PHP} \cdot \mathsf{Wordpress} \cdot \mathsf{Bootstrap} \cdot \mathsf{Web} \ \mathsf{hosting}$

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend · React Native · ReactJS · Typescript · $Storybook \cdot GraphQL \cdot HTML \cdot Angular \cdot AngularJS \cdot$ Leaflet maps · i18n · RESTful API · Sass · Material UI · Here Maps · Javascript · jQuery · Next.js · OpenAl API infrastructure · Parcel · Firebase · Fastlane · Webpack Vercel testing Jest Karma Selenium tool · Datadog · i18n · Gitlab style · Scss · Bootstrap · D3 · Responsive Design · Sass · Material UI · CSS · Mocha · Facebook API · Twitter API · Yammer API · Java · Oracle D · Activiti · Alfresco · Tailwind runtime NodeJS accessibility · a11y cms · Wordpress

EDUCATION

Master in IoT, Domotics and Smart Cities

Salamanca University (Spain)

Spanish English

German

Erasmus Program

Technische Universität Dresde (Germany)

Bachelor Degree in Industrial Engineering

Malaga University (Spain)

